<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bretward James</title>
    <link>https://bretwardjames.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bretward James</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 22:34:34 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bretwardjames.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stripe is Dope - Here is Why</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2019-02-11-stripe-is-dope-here-is-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 22:34:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2019-02-11-stripe-is-dope-here-is-why/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiring an Agency vs Hiring In-House Staff</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2019-02-06-hiring-an-agency-vs-hiring-in-house-staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 22:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2019-02-06-hiring-an-agency-vs-hiring-in-house-staff/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people wonder whether it&amp;rsquo;s wiser to hire an agency (for the expertise) vs hiring full-time staff (for the commitment). I&amp;rsquo;ve been on both sides of this question. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last 15 years as an agency/freelancer, and I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you, it&amp;rsquo;s not all roses and kittens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Like Me (or don&#39;t) S3E3 - Sure, but do YOU respect you?</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tlms3e3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 04:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tlms3e3/</guid>
      <description>https://anchor.fm/thinklikeme/episodes/S3E3---Sure--but-do-YOU-respect-you-e343lf More often than any of us is willing to admit, the reason we don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;get the respect we deserve&amp;rdquo; has nothing to do with anyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Like Me (or don&#39;t) S3E2 - The Truth Doesn&#39;t Really Matter</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tlms3e2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tlms3e2/</guid>
      <description>https://anchor.fm/thinklikeme/episodes/S3E2---The-Truth-Doesnt-Really-Matter-e33qrk I think we talk too much about the &amp;ldquo;honorable pursuit of Truth&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think truth matters nearly as much as we tell ourselves it does. It does, however, give us a nice excuse to ignore our very real emotions by bottling them up until they inevitably explode, destroying most of what makes sense in life. Have a listen. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light - Foto Friday #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/light-foto-friday-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/light-foto-friday-1/</guid>
      <description>This photo was taken at Balboa Park in San Diego. I was at the park playing badminton of all things, and I turned to see a man with his Australian Shepherd playing fetch with a frisbee.
Wick hadn’t joined our little family just yet, and being as obsessed with Aussies as I am, I was mesmerized.
A photo can’t really express the feeling of being in that spot, watching that happen, but it’s the next best thing to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of SixthDivision - Throwback Thursday #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/throwback-thursday-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/throwback-thursday-1/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook AMA (Campaign Inception) - inFrequently Asked Questions #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/facebook-ama-campaign-inception-infrequently-asked-questions-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/facebook-ama-campaign-inception-infrequently-asked-questions-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Ads On A Fixed Budget - Tech Tips #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/facebook-ads-on-a-fixed-budget-tech-tips-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 22:34:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/facebook-ads-on-a-fixed-budget-tech-tips-1/</guid>
      <description>If you’re running Facebook ads, you probably don’t have an unlimited budget. (side note - if you do have an unlimited budget, my hat goes off to you. also, you should give me some)
The problem with being on a limited budget is keeping track of how much you’re spending across the various campaigns that you’re running, not to mention the posts that you’re boosting.
However, there’s a little hack you can use to make sure that no matter what you do, your monthly ad spend will always be the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wife, The Mistress, and The Vice - Morning Coffee #37</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-37/</guid>
      <description>What I’m about to share with you is the result of many, many years of life bashing me over the head trying to get me to understand this simple principle.
I am not someone who enjoys saying “No”.
I don’t like thinking (or thinking that someone else is thinking) that I’m not capable of doing something.
I say yes to everything, because I see every request as a challenge, and I don’t back down from challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Agency That SHOULD Exist - Morning Coffee #36</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 16:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-36/</guid>
      <description>So I have this vision for an agency that would solve a MAJOR problem for freelance web talent (copywriters, designers, developers, marketers, etc).
The inspiration for this agency comes from a few different places:
1. Hired Gun (on Netflix) This movie is all about the studio musicians that often are the workhorses behind the popular musicians that we celebrate.
This movie tells the story of some of the greatest musicians alive who just happen to be better at literally playing second fiddle to the more popular names, and therefore we don’t know who they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SixthDivision Academy v1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/work/6d-acadamy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2013 22:34:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/work/6d-acadamy/</guid>
      <description>If you’re running Facebook ads, you probably don’t have an unlimited budget. (side note - if you do have an unlimited budget, my hat goes off to you. also, you should give me some)
The problem with being on a limited budget is keeping track of how much you’re spending across the various campaigns that you’re running, not to mention the posts that you’re boosting.
However, there’s a little hack you can use to make sure that no matter what you do, your monthly ad spend will always be the same.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>