<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bretward James</title>
    <link>https://bretwardjames.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bretward James</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 22:34:34 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bretwardjames.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Stripe is Dope - Here is Why</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2019-02-11-stripe-is-dope-here-is-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 22:34:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2019-02-11-stripe-is-dope-here-is-why/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiring an Agency vs Hiring In-House Staff</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2019-02-06-hiring-an-agency-vs-hiring-in-house-staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 22:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2019-02-06-hiring-an-agency-vs-hiring-in-house-staff/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people wonder whether it&amp;rsquo;s wiser to hire an agency (for the expertise) vs hiring full-time staff (for the commitment). I&amp;rsquo;ve been on both sides of this question. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last 15 years as an agency/freelancer, and I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you, it&amp;rsquo;s not all roses and kittens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Like Me (or don&#39;t) S3E3 - Sure, but do YOU respect you?</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tlms3e3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 04:09:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tlms3e3/</guid>
      <description>https://anchor.fm/thinklikeme/episodes/S3E3---Sure--but-do-YOU-respect-you-e343lf More often than any of us is willing to admit, the reason we don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;get the respect we deserve&amp;rdquo; has nothing to do with anyone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think Like Me (or don&#39;t) S3E2 - The Truth Doesn&#39;t Really Matter</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tlms3e2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tlms3e2/</guid>
      <description>https://anchor.fm/thinklikeme/episodes/S3E2---The-Truth-Doesnt-Really-Matter-e33qrk I think we talk too much about the &amp;ldquo;honorable pursuit of Truth&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t think truth matters nearly as much as we tell ourselves it does. It does, however, give us a nice excuse to ignore our very real emotions by bottling them up until they inevitably explode, destroying most of what makes sense in life. Have a listen. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light - Foto Friday #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/light-foto-friday-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/light-foto-friday-1/</guid>
      <description>This photo was taken at Balboa Park in San Diego. I was at the park playing badminton of all things, and I turned to see a man with his Australian Shepherd playing fetch with a frisbee.
Wick hadn’t joined our little family just yet, and being as obsessed with Aussies as I am, I was mesmerized.
A photo can’t really express the feeling of being in that spot, watching that happen, but it’s the next best thing to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginnings of SixthDivision - Throwback Thursday #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/throwback-thursday-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/throwback-thursday-1/</guid>
      <description>   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook AMA (Campaign Inception) - inFrequently Asked Questions #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/facebook-ama-campaign-inception-infrequently-asked-questions-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/facebook-ama-campaign-inception-infrequently-asked-questions-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Ads On A Fixed Budget - Tech Tips #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 22:34:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/about/</guid>
      <description>If you’re running Facebook ads, you probably don’t have an unlimited budget. (side note - if you do have an unlimited budget, my hat goes off to you. also, you should give me some)
The problem with being on a limited budget is keeping track of how much you’re spending across the various campaigns that you’re running, not to mention the posts that you’re boosting.
However, there’s a little hack you can use to make sure that no matter what you do, your monthly ad spend will always be the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Ads On A Fixed Budget - Tech Tips #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/facebook-ads-on-a-fixed-budget-tech-tips-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 22:34:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/facebook-ads-on-a-fixed-budget-tech-tips-1/</guid>
      <description>If you’re running Facebook ads, you probably don’t have an unlimited budget. (side note - if you do have an unlimited budget, my hat goes off to you. also, you should give me some)
The problem with being on a limited budget is keeping track of how much you’re spending across the various campaigns that you’re running, not to mention the posts that you’re boosting.
However, there’s a little hack you can use to make sure that no matter what you do, your monthly ad spend will always be the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wife, The Mistress, and The Vice - Morning Coffee #37</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-37/</guid>
      <description>What I’m about to share with you is the result of many, many years of life bashing me over the head trying to get me to understand this simple principle.
I am not someone who enjoys saying “No”.
I don’t like thinking (or thinking that someone else is thinking) that I’m not capable of doing something.
I say yes to everything, because I see every request as a challenge, and I don’t back down from challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Agency That SHOULD Exist - Morning Coffee #36</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 16:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-36/</guid>
      <description>So I have this vision for an agency that would solve a MAJOR problem for freelance web talent (copywriters, designers, developers, marketers, etc).
The inspiration for this agency comes from a few different places:
1. Hired Gun (on Netflix) This movie is all about the studio musicians that often are the workhorses behind the popular musicians that we celebrate.
This movie tells the story of some of the greatest musicians alive who just happen to be better at literally playing second fiddle to the more popular names, and therefore we don’t know who they are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Certification (it&#39;s just a piece of paper) - Morning Coffee #32</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 16:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/morning-coffee-32/</guid>
      <description>Do you have a college degree? What about an industry certification?
Did you notice that it’s possible to get either of those without really knowing anything about the subject matter?
Or, conversely, remember that scene from Good Will Hunting, where he tells the Harvard student that he wasted $150,000 on an education he could have gotten for $1.50 in late fees at the public library?
In truth, college educations and industry certifications are unfortunately not synonymous with competence or expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Some Funny Stories From My 3rd Stint at Infusionsoft - Morning Coffee #31</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/just-some-funny-stories-from-my-3rd-stint-at-infusionsoft-morning-coffee-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 16:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/just-some-funny-stories-from-my-3rd-stint-at-infusionsoft-morning-coffee-31/</guid>
      <description>This starts out with me having to interview to get a job back at Infusionsoft. (Shout out to Scott Morrison)
1:15 - I am asked to stay at Infusionsoft for more than 2 years (I didn&amp;rsquo;t)
2:24 - I forget how English works
2:30 - I set up a standing desk WAY before it was cool
2:55 - I knock the coffee right off the counter - quite messy haha</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Responsibility of Having an Opinion is Expressing it Honestly - Morning Coffee #30</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-responsibility-of-having-an-opinion-is-expressing-it-honestly-morning-coffee-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 16:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-responsibility-of-having-an-opinion-is-expressing-it-honestly-morning-coffee-30/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always resisted the idea that you should keep your opinions to yourself when it will rock the boat or cause conflict.
I really dislike the idea of censoring my actual thoughts and feelings for the sake of some arbitrary standard of &amp;ldquo;peace&amp;rdquo;.
I just don&amp;rsquo;t think we have time for that.
Whether we allow ourselves to believe it or not - our time is limited, and every moment of growth that we waste by hiding our actual opinions and thoughts is a moment we can never get back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;There&#39;s No Money In Music&#34; - Morning Coffee #29</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/theres-no-money-in-music-morning-coffee-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 17:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/theres-no-money-in-music-morning-coffee-29/</guid>
      <description>I came out of high school really wanting to go into music education. I wanted to be a choir teacher at some junior college somewhere, and eventually get the opportunity to conduct a university choir.
And I was GOOD, by the way. Still am, although I&amp;rsquo;m out of practice.
But somewhere along the line, I let someone convince me that there was no money in music.
And from that moment on, it became &amp;ldquo;clear&amp;rdquo; to me that the right choice was to pursue law, and leave music behind altogether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove the Friction - Morning Coffee #28</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/11/19/remove-the-friction-morning-coffee-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 20:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/11/19/remove-the-friction-morning-coffee-28/</guid>
      <description>The number one obstacle to forward motion in any endeavor is friction.
We expend a lot of energy to overcome the friction in our lives, but we tend not to do much to remove the friction altogether.
We set goals, we develop discipline, we push and push and overcome, but think how much further we&amp;rsquo;d go, given that same amount of energy, if the friction was reduced by half?
I have experienced this in so many different ways and across so many years that it&amp;rsquo;s become extremely clear to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People Don&#39;t Think Like You Think They Do - Morning Coffee #27</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/people-dont-think-like-you-think-they-do-morning-coffee-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 16:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/people-dont-think-like-you-think-they-do-morning-coffee-27/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I&amp;rsquo;m still surprised when I find out that people don&amp;rsquo;t always think exactly like me.
I should know better - I&amp;rsquo;ve left 3 companies, a marriage, and a church - all at least partly because one or both of us couldn&amp;rsquo;t get on board with the way the other was thinking.
And yet, life has a way of continuing to put people and situations in our path to remind us of simple things like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maybe Peripherals Aren&#39;t ALL Bad - Morning Coffee #26</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/maybe-peripherals-arent-all-bad-morning-coffee-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 17:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/maybe-peripherals-arent-all-bad-morning-coffee-26/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve raved against depending on peripherals lately, but I think there is a caveat to that. I think depending on tools and gadgets can be fine if they are actually essential to the finished product.
But most of the time, we just hide behind them in an attempt to hide the actual product.
I have been as guilty (if not MORE) than anyone of hiding behind fancy gizmos so that the real me wasn&amp;rsquo;t exposed, because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very confident in myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Your Footing First (also, stop making assumptions) - Morning Coffee #25</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/find-your-footing-first-also-stop-making-assumptions-morning-coffee-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 16:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/find-your-footing-first-also-stop-making-assumptions-morning-coffee-25/</guid>
      <description>I seriously injured my knee when I was in Ukraine.
I got there right at the beginning of the coldest winter in almost 50 years. Snow, ice, the whole 9.
Being an AZ boy, these concepts were extremely foreign to me. I had no idea there’s a difference between walking on pavement, walking on freshly fallen snow, and walking on roads where the snow has compacted into ice.
The thing is, in that third situation, the ice is usually disguised with a thin layer of snow, making it really easy to mistake for freshly fallen snow (especially to a n00b like me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Number One Killer of Long-Term Creativity</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-number-one-killer-of-long-term-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 23:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-number-one-killer-of-long-term-creativity/</guid>
      <description>People spend countless hours and energy building their “setup”, thereby rendering themselves immobile when it comes to the actual act of creation.
Sometimes it manifests as buying actual peripherals for their computer setup (the latest monitor, the nicest MacBook, the best webcam, the nicest microphone, etc).
Sometimes it’s a little less subtle. Sometimes people are always looking for ways to repurpose what someone else has done, instead of trying to create something of their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Did After I Left Infusionsoft the FIRST Time: Morning Coffee #24</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/what-i-did-after-i-left-infusionsoft-the-first-time-morning-coffee-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/what-i-did-after-i-left-infusionsoft-the-first-time-morning-coffee-24/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people say you should make your goals public. I think the idea is that you feel more accountable when someone else knows what you’re trying to do.
Personally, I don’t like doing this any more. I used to share my grand plans and huge goals, but recently I’ve shifted to letting my actions tell people about my goals.
You have to be careful with goals - sometimes saying your goal out loud can trick your brain into taking credit for the goal before you’ve even gotten started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugar PSA - Morning Coffee #23</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/11/18/sugar-psa-morning-coffee-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/11/18/sugar-psa-morning-coffee-23/</guid>
      <description>Public Service Announcement Regarding Sugar
We take a slight break from our usual Morning Coffee show for a PSA about sugar :)
In the span of my life, science has changed its mind about sugar about 12 times.
Then, more recently, it became common knowledge that some of the early “science” was influenced heavily by parts of the food industry that were heavy on added sugar in their foods.
I haven’t done my homework on reading the studies or the research, but here’s what I know:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Cost of Entrepreneurship</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-hidden-cost-of-entrepreneurship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-hidden-cost-of-entrepreneurship/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life, Lemons, and a Change of Scenery - Morning Coffee #22</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/life-lemons-and-a-change-of-scenery-morning-coffee-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/life-lemons-and-a-change-of-scenery-morning-coffee-22/</guid>
      <description>When life gives you lemons….
I’m not sure there is a more intensely platitudinous (how’s that for a GREAT word, eh?) saying. There are lot of good ones, but in my opinion, this one takes the cake.
And yet - if you look past the cliche, and look past all of the empty uses, there is an extremely valuable (and practical) lesson.
The last week it’s pretty much been raining lemons over here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation Was My FIRST Business Language (Thanks to Infusionsoft): Morning Coffee #21</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/automation-was-my-first-business-language-thanks-to-infusionsoft-morning-coffee-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/automation-was-my-first-business-language-thanks-to-infusionsoft-morning-coffee-21/</guid>
      <description>Если это понимаешь, молодец.
I imagine most of you went straight to Google on that one (unless you already understand Russian, in which case I already congratulated you).
When I learned Russian, I was forced to go deeper than just the words they were using. Russians have an entirely different way of speaking. Everything from the way the sentences are structured to the inflection of the sentences.
If I tried to just replace English words with Russian words, but keep everything else the same, nobody would understand me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That Time Clate Introduced the Rowan Award - Morning Coffee #20</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/that-time-clate-introduced-the-rowan-award-morning-coffee-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 16:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/that-time-clate-introduced-the-rowan-award-morning-coffee-20/</guid>
      <description>If you wanted a meatball sub, how many Subways would you be willing to visit in order to get it?
Seriously, think about it.
Let’s say the first subway you go to is out of bread.
The second is out of marinara sauce.
The third is out of meatballs.
The fourth is out of cheese.
Maybe you think after the second store, you’d probably just pick a different sandwich that they DO have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That One Time My Video Took Down The Infusionsoft Website - Morning Coffee #19</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/that-one-time-my-video-took-down-the-infusionsoft-website-morning-coffee-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/that-one-time-my-video-took-down-the-infusionsoft-website-morning-coffee-19/</guid>
      <description>So there was this one time that I can back into the support office after getting a drink of water. We had a little dowel that we used to use in meetings as the &amp;ldquo;Talking Stick&amp;rdquo;.
I picked it up and started drumming on the chair and on my cup and on the desk and it turned out that Clint was recording the whole thing.
A couple of weeks later, I uploaded the video to what I thought was my own website, but turned out to be the main directory of the Infusionsoft website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infusionsoft: The Early Days (vol 3) - Morning Coffee #18</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/infusionsoft-the-early-days-vol-3-morning-coffee-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 18:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/infusionsoft-the-early-days-vol-3-morning-coffee-18/</guid>
      <description>ARCHIVE FOOTAGE ALERT!
Today&amp;rsquo;s episode of Morning Coffee features some archive footage of the original Infusionsoft team. Kyle Leavitt, Nathan Leavitt, Jeremy Gurr,Tara LaRue Stradling, Eric Martineau, Scott Martineau, Aaron Halderman, Cody Jones, TJ Lorenzen, and the ever-present cameraman, Clint Garner.
&amp;ldquo;Company Culture&amp;rdquo; has become more and more of a commonplace consideration for companies.
Seems like nowadays every company has their equivalent of an &amp;ldquo;open floor plan&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;cereal bar&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;game room&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being an Entrepreneur is Like Training For a Fight</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/being-an-entrepreneur-is-like-training-for-a-fight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/being-an-entrepreneur-is-like-training-for-a-fight/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Everybody has a plan until they get punched in the face.&amp;rdquo; That quote is commonly attributed to Mike Tyson, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure Mike&amp;rsquo;s opponents understood this better than he ever did. Either way, I can personally verify that this is absolutely true.
Once that first bell rings, and the adrenaline hits you, all of your plans go right out the window. It&amp;rsquo;s almost like you lose control of your brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infusionsoft: The Early Days Vol. 2 - Morning Coffee #17</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/infusionsoft-the-early-days-vol-2-morning-coffee-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 15:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/infusionsoft-the-early-days-vol-2-morning-coffee-17/</guid>
      <description>The friction that exists between sales and fulfillment is, although annoying for both parties, integral to growth. That&amp;rsquo;s especially true for a fledgling tech company like Infusionsoft in the early days.
After Dave and Cody joined the team, I remember there being a good deal of animosity between us (the support/training/fulfillment team) and sales.
They were so focused on making the sale that they would promise things that we (the support team) weren&amp;rsquo;t fully prepared to deliver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infusionsoft: The Early Days - Morning Coffee # 16</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/infusionsoft-the-early-days-morning-coffee-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 17:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/infusionsoft-the-early-days-morning-coffee-16/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s crazy to realize how much my early days at Infusionsoft have influenced the rest of my life.
When I started, there were 7 of us:
4 Brothers (Scott, Eric, Brad, and me)
1 In-Law (Clate)
1 Neighbor (Tara)
and Jeremy
I don&amp;rsquo;t believe Jeremy was related in any way, but he might as well have been.
I always knew that Infusionsoft started as a &amp;ldquo;family&amp;rdquo; business, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate how true that was until this morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S2E5 - Ohhhhh THAT&#39;S what I&#39;ve been doing wrong... - Think Like Me (or don&#39;t)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/podcast/s2e5-ohhhhh-thats-what-ive-been-doing-wrong-think-like-me-or-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 13:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/podcast/s2e5-ohhhhh-thats-what-ive-been-doing-wrong-think-like-me-or-dont/</guid>
      <description>Alcoholics or addicts of any kind are taught to completely remove the offending substance from their life. And stay away from them like the plague and create an alternative lifestyle because they are powerless. For some reason, that particular vice has power over them.
And I think for me, it&amp;rsquo;s credit.
Credit, both the financial and metaphorical version of credit, has been a huge vice, something that I&amp;rsquo;ve never really managed well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That job I had before Infusionsoft - Morning Coffee #15</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/that-job-i-had-before-infusionsoft-morning-coffee-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/that-job-i-had-before-infusionsoft-morning-coffee-15/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of Morning Coffee, I tell the story of my first real job (pre-Infusionsoft).
My little brother, Craig, and I, worked for a guy making copies of antlers.
Yep, you read that right - antlers.
As in deer antlers.
Lots of fun anecdotes in the story (definitely you should check it out), but there was one thing I mentioned that I want to call out.
When I left working for that guy to go start work at Infusionsoft, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that it was polite to give 2 weeks notice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That time I quit marketing - Morning Coffee #14</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/that-time-i-quit-marketing-morning-coffee-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/that-time-i-quit-marketing-morning-coffee-14/</guid>
      <description>I have a sneaking suspicion (based only on my own experience) that most frustration is actually based in insecurity.
For example:
At the beginning of 2017, I quit the marketing game altogether.
I liked to say to myself that it was because I was fed up with the charlatanism and douchebagery that is so commonplace in the marketing world.
And that was kind of true.
Chicanery doth abound here.
However, the larger reason why I left was out of fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No, YOU do it - Morning Coffee #13</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/no-you-do-it-morning-coffee-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/no-you-do-it-morning-coffee-13/</guid>
      <description>Just because you have a reason or an excuse for why your customers are upset with you doesn&amp;rsquo;t absolve you of the responsibility of fixing it.
I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how often I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with a client, something broke, and although it wasn&amp;rsquo;t directly my fault, I had to take responsibility for fixing the problem.
Even if there is no way that I could have foreseen that particular issue, it fell under the scope of my responsibility, and therefore I was responsible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everybody needs a support system - Morning Coffee #12</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/everybody-needs-a-support-system-morning-coffee-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/everybody-needs-a-support-system-morning-coffee-12/</guid>
      <description>The way you feel about what you&amp;rsquo;re doing is soooo closely linked to how well you do it.
If you feel like you suck at something, the likelihood that you&amp;rsquo;re going to do it well is slim to none at best.
Keeping a positive attitude can have a MASSIVE impact on your output.
Surrounding yourself with people that you trust can help get you through the days when you think you suck, because those people can remind you of your potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People follow good people - Morning Coffee #11</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/people-follow-good-people-morning-coffee-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/people-follow-good-people-morning-coffee-11/</guid>
      <description>This should be obvious, I think, but here it is:
Be a good person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop trying to not do work</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/stop-trying-to-not-do-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 03:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/stop-trying-to-not-do-work/</guid>
      <description>For the last decade, we&amp;rsquo;ve been brainwashed (myself included, by the way) into thinking that charging more for less work was the way to scale.
Hell, I have taught that same principle from stage on multiple occasions. I totally bought into the culture of charging more &amp;lsquo;because you can&amp;rsquo;.
Why do we do that?
Wanna know what I think? I think it&amp;rsquo;s because we are deathly afraid of the one thing we should be embracing more than anything else:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I knew I was going to leave the Mormon church when I was 12 - Morning Coffee #10</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/i-knew-i-was-going-to-leave-the-mormon-church-when-i-was-12-morning-coffee-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/i-knew-i-was-going-to-leave-the-mormon-church-when-i-was-12-morning-coffee-10/</guid>
      <description>I am usually the first to disregard my own instincts.
I love making calculated decisions based on data and analysis.
In fact, my default setting is pretty much always set to &amp;ldquo;question everything always&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s especially true of my own thoughts.
But I think maybe I lean too far in that direction. I&amp;rsquo;ve made plenty of decisions in my life that it took me several years to finally put into action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dues of Entrepreneurship - Morning Coffee #9</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-dues-of-entrepreneurship-morning-coffee-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-dues-of-entrepreneurship-morning-coffee-9/</guid>
      <description>I never liked the idea of &amp;ldquo;paying my dues&amp;rdquo;. I always thought that was beneath me for some reason.
I just wanted people to notice what I was doing and give me the credit that I thought I deserved.
Ironically enough, although I was (and still am) KILLING it in the work I was doing, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done ANYTHING to deserve the notoriety or credit I was after.
Sure, I have always gotten a lot of referrals for business because I do good work, but what I really WANTED was for someone to ask me to speak from stage, or come out and present to 50 staff members, or co-present on a webinar to a couple thousand people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You DON’T Get to Do Whatever You Want - Morning Coffee #8</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/you-dont-get-to-do-whatever-you-want-morning-coffee-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/you-dont-get-to-do-whatever-you-want-morning-coffee-8/</guid>
      <description>Entrepreneurship is NOT about &amp;ldquo;doing whatever you want&amp;rdquo;.
Sure, you get to choose the general direction of where you want to go, but once you&amp;rsquo;ve locked that in, you are extremely restricted in the day-to-day.
You don&amp;rsquo;t get to say,
&amp;ldquo;I want to fight Conor McGregor in 6 months,&amp;rdquo;
AND ALSO SAY
&amp;ldquo;I want to sleep in today and go to the fair and have funnel cake.&amp;rdquo;
If you decide you want to fight Conor, you give up the freedom to have funnel cake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Day After The Bad Day - Morning Coffee #7 (Sue&#39;s day Tuesday)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-day-after-the-bad-day-morning-coffee-7-sues-day-tuesday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-day-after-the-bad-day-morning-coffee-7-sues-day-tuesday/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes the cure for stress and overwhelm is to just press on.
In my case, a conversation about something completely unrelated with a friend I hadn&amp;rsquo;t spoken to in nearly a decade brought me back around.
Not saying it works every time, but having a distraction helps. And also, just keep swimming.
The important thing is to not let the opportunity to learn and improve pass you by.
Bad days are lessons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This started out as one of the bad days - Morning Coffee #6</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/this-started-out-as-one-of-the-bad-days-morning-coffee-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/this-started-out-as-one-of-the-bad-days-morning-coffee-6/</guid>
      <description>Some days you wake up and it honestly feels like your world is crashing down around you.
Most of the time, your mind is blowing the reality out of proportion, but it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to keep that perspective when you&amp;rsquo;re in that moment.
I don&amp;rsquo;t have any answers or magic cures, but hopefully if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling that overwhelm, you can take solace in the fact that you&amp;rsquo;re not alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear, comfort, and luck - Morning Coffee #5</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fear-comfort-and-luck-morning-coffee-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fear-comfort-and-luck-morning-coffee-5/</guid>
      <description>Last night I listened to a Gary Vee episode that is blowing up social media today.
He and his guest gave a “lucky” caller the break she desperately wanted.
A lot of people will say (and already are saying) that she got lucky.
I disagree.
Here’s the video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skJny&amp;hellip;
Check out bretmartineau.com/podcast</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation, Upwork and the future of freelancing, and how “CEO” has no meaning - Morning Coffee #4</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/isolation-upwork-and-the-future-of-freelancing-and-how-ceo-has-no-meaning-morning-coffee-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/isolation-upwork-and-the-future-of-freelancing-and-how-ceo-has-no-meaning-morning-coffee-4/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to being self-employed or working remotely that goes unaddressed. Never fear, I shall address it!!
Also, I&amp;rsquo;m really REALLY over being a &amp;ldquo;CEO&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wake Up, It&#39;s Wednesday - Morning Coffee #3</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/wake-up-its-wednesday-morning-coffee-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/wake-up-its-wednesday-morning-coffee-3/</guid>
      <description>I discuss a change that I&amp;rsquo;m making to my business based on a conversation with an expert that I should have had 2 years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday (Sue&#39;s Day) Tools vs Raw Materials? - Morning Coffee #2</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tuesday-sues-day-tools-vs-raw-materials-morning-coffee-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tuesday-sues-day-tools-vs-raw-materials-morning-coffee-2/</guid>
      <description>Follow-up on yesterday&amp;rsquo;s video features a cameo by none other than Sue herself.
I talk more about the benefit of streamlining and simplifying life, and then geek out on Gary Vee vids (as per the usual).
Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to the video I mention in the vid: https://youtu.be/0e8COwvlFUc?t=2m45s</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Getting Rid of Most of My Coffee Gear - Morning Coffee #1</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/why-im-getting-rid-of-most-of-my-coffee-gear-morning-coffee-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/why-im-getting-rid-of-most-of-my-coffee-gear-morning-coffee-1/</guid>
      <description>I realized that I don&amp;rsquo;t really like Moka, French Press, or any coffee other than pour over. Also, living in a 1-bedroom apartment in San Diego, I don&amp;rsquo;t have unlimited space. So I made a decision to trade $300 worth of coffee stuff for a $40 setup and I love it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Fight? - Conclusion (part 5 of 5)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fight-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 19:50:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fight-5/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to come up with the best way to conclude this story/explanation of why I fight. Then I saw something that sums it up perfectly.
Here&amp;rsquo;s why I fight:
 ![](http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5b29b282b27e39d3891a137e/5b29d50ac07b083624e43ad2/5b66029f70a6adef3beca81d/1533412012663/giphy.gif)  YOLO, people.
YOLO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Fight? - Reason #3: Fear (part 4 of 5)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fight-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 15:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fight-4/</guid>
      <description>Ok for this one, I have to go back in time a bit. All the way back to when I was a wee lad. We used to take a lot of trips to the lake back then and on one such occasion, some of the other boys and I decided to try cliff jumping.
&amp;ldquo;Cliff&amp;rdquo; is a bit of a misnomer. It was more like jumping off a small boulder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Fight? - Reason #2: Health (part 3 of 5)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fight-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 18:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fight-3/</guid>
      <description>There is an interesting correlation (for me, anyway) between fighting and my overall health. It makes perfect sense - there&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;in shape&amp;rdquo; and then there&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;in fight shape&amp;rdquo;. Preparing for a fight means getting ready for as many different possibilities as you can, and most importantly being ready to last longer than the other guy.
I know that using weight as an indicator for health is generally inaccurate, but in my case it&amp;rsquo;s the best indication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Fight? - Reason #1: Humanity (part 2 of 5)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/why-fight-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 22:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/why-fight-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Reason #1: Humanity The thing about Muay Thai, and all combat sports really, is that it&amp;rsquo;s so purely human. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing but glove and sweat between you and your opponent. There are no tricks, no weapons, it&amp;rsquo;s skin against skin alone.
 ![](http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5b29b282b27e39d3891a137e/5b29d50ac07b083624e43ad2/5b3408a2f950b7fe67ed2731/1530136760030/Screen+Shot+2018-06-27+at+2.58.39+PM.png.39+PM.png?format=original)  It&amp;rsquo;s just you and what you are physically capable of doing with your body and your opponent and what he (or she) is capable of doing with his (hers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Fight? - The Back Story (part 1 of 5)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fight-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 15:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fight-1/</guid>
      <description>Since I got started training Muay Thai, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a lot of different types of reactions from people who have known me my whole life. Everything from dumbfounded surprise to concerned criticism to unabashed pride.
For a long time, I tended to ignore the surprise and the criticism and revel in the pride, telling myself that since I viewed this newfound lifestyle as a complete positive, anyone that didn&amp;rsquo;t share that view wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth listening to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be You, 100% and Without Apology</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/6/20/be-you-100-and-without-apology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 18:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/6/20/be-you-100-and-without-apology/</guid>
      <description>I recently ran a promotion. Well, it was more of an &amp;ldquo;Announcement of Services&amp;rdquo; if anything, but it ran on LinkedIn and Facebook. On LinkedIn it was sent as a message:
 ![](http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5b29b282b27e39d3891a137e/5b29d50ac07b083624e43ad2/5b2a881788251b2811b16615/1529514661799/Screen+Shot+2018-05-04+at+11.15.02+AM.png.02+AM.png?format=original)   And on Facebook it was a regular ad, leading to a messaging reply:
  ![](http://static1.squarespace.com/static/5b29b282b27e39d3891a137e/5b29d50ac07b083624e43ad2/5b2a8871f950b773dc236f90/1529514127219/Screen+Shot+2018-05-04+at+11.24.17+AM.png.17+AM.png?format=original)   Of the 15 people that have responded so far on either platform, 2 of the initial ones had very specific suggestions for how I could &amp;ldquo;improve&amp;rdquo; the ad:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Trim Your Nose Hairs with a Chain Saw</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/6/20/dont-trim-your-nose-hairs-with-a-chain-saw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 16:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/6/20/dont-trim-your-nose-hairs-with-a-chain-saw/</guid>
      <description>Ever woke up in the morning and thought:
Hmmm&amp;hellip;my nose hairs are out of control, I wonder if there&amp;rsquo;s enough gas in the chainsaw for a trim? Probably not. I&amp;rsquo;d imagine you&amp;rsquo;d go into the bathroom, find the appropriate tool (tweezers, trimmers, etc) for that specific job.
It&amp;rsquo;s not so much that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a chainsaw, it&amp;rsquo;s more that you don&amp;rsquo;t need it for that.
Why, then, do so many business owners like yourself pay outrageous prices for services they don&amp;rsquo;t actually need?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Steps Back, 5 Steps Forward - a business video shot in an unbusiness setting</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/4/9/2-steps-back-5-steps-forward-a-business-video-shot-in-an-unbusiness-setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/2018/4/9/2-steps-back-5-steps-forward-a-business-video-shot-in-an-unbusiness-setting/</guid>
      <description>This is a video about BUSINESS, shot in an extremely UNBUSINESS setting. Sometimes the best way forward is actually to turn around and reset.
Sometimes I have my best thoughts when I&amp;rsquo;m working out. And this is how I work out.
I was walking my dog one day and these two ladies stopped me and asked which way to Balboa Park.
I turned around and pointed the way I&amp;rsquo;d just been coming, and said it&amp;rsquo;s directly that way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereal Extent (a name that only AI could choose)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/ethereal-extent-a-name-that-only-ai-could-choose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/ethereal-extent-a-name-that-only-ai-could-choose/</guid>
      <description>Trying something totally new on this one. The beat and electronic vibe didn&amp;rsquo;t really speak to much to a melodic overlay, but you all should know by now how much I love hearing myself talk.
So I kind of put the two together.
Enjoy.
PS I&amp;rsquo;ll have the full 2 hours of putting this song together this morning. Uncut, raw. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of fun, actually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine (a grooveTASTIC cover version)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/shine-a-groovetastic-cover-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 02:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/shine-a-groovetastic-cover-version/</guid>
      <description>A reimagined version of Collective Soul&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Shine&amp;rdquo;.
A lot of cover artists take a minimalist approach, stripping the song down to its essentials and playing simple chords with excellent vocalisms.
I like to be different (because I&amp;rsquo;m crazy) so this is a small example of a more lateral reimagining of one of the greatest songs of all time.
Enjoy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice and training and things (Think Like Me - 17)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/practice-and-training-and-things-think-like-me-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 05:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/practice-and-training-and-things-think-like-me-17/</guid>
      <description>The podcast is back! I ramble about practice and study and training, and even do some piano playing! (the first 5 minutes are cut off in the audio, but you can get them in the Youtube video)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology, Fear, and Embracing Change</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/technology-fear-and-embracing-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 01:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/technology-fear-and-embracing-change/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about how far voice transcription technology has come in the last decade. I remember when my dad first got the Dragon NaturallySpeaking software, or whatever it was called, for our old PC that was running Windows 95. That program was terrible and you had to speak soooo slowly. It was a nightmare to use. But now, I&amp;rsquo;m literally dictating this blog post to a Google doc on my phone as I drive home from the gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TUF Viewing Party and things (Think Like Me - 16)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tuf-viewing-party-and-things-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 05:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tuf-viewing-party-and-things-3/</guid>
      <description>Language Warning Denis, Michelle and I watch some amazing fights on The Ultimate Fighter and then discuss some stuff about training Muay Thai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TUF Viewing Party and things (Think Like Me - 15)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tuf-viewing-party-and-things-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 05:46:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tuf-viewing-party-and-things-2/</guid>
      <description>LANGUAGE ALERT Denis and I watch the latest episode of TUF - and we&amp;rsquo;re joined by Michelle for part of it! We also watched a little bit of Bellator MMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TUF Viewing Party and things (Think Like Me 14)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tuf-viewing-party-and-things-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 05:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/tuf-viewing-party-and-things-1/</guid>
      <description>Language Warning Denis and I watch the latest episode of The Ultimate Fighter and provide our commentary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music and frustration and things (Think Like Me - 13)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/music-and-frustration-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 05:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/music-and-frustration-and-things/</guid>
      <description>I dink around on the guitar and piano a bit, but mostly chat about how I wish people would stop being afraid to say things to me for fear of backlash or retaliation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guilt and music and things (Think Like Me - 12)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/guilt-and-music-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 05:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/guilt-and-music-and-things/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I showcase some of the new changes to the ever-upgrading setup (some geetar action), as well as show a cover of a Cat Stevens song and ramble about relationships, guilt, and slowing everything down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language is useless and things (Think Like Me - 11)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/language-is-useless-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2016 05:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/language-is-useless-and-things/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I ramble on about politics and how spoken language is useless. Also, Batman makes an appearance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sparring and relationships and things (Think Like Me - 10)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/sparring-and-relationships-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 05:18:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/sparring-and-relationships-and-things/</guid>
      <description>In this episode I ramble about sparring and relationships. And some other stuff I think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pokemon and politics and things (Think Like Me - 9)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/pokemon-and-politics-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 05:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/pokemon-and-politics-and-things/</guid>
      <description>In this episode I ramble about Pokemon Go, politics, and Trillary. Or Hillump, depending on how you see it. Featuring a Facebook Live session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a song live and things (Think Like Me - 8)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/writing-a-song-live-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 05:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/writing-a-song-live-and-things/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, I start out rambling about dating and Muay Thai, and then decide to write a song live for the recording. So I spend an hour or so and write a rough first draft of a full song. Denis joins me for part of it and helps out with the lyrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear and respect and things (Think Like Me - 7)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fear-and-respect-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 03:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/fear-and-respect-and-things/</guid>
      <description>In this episode I ramble on about culture and counterculture and counter-counterculture, as well as fear and respect, and of course how Muay Thai is the perfect metaphor for life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Interview and spirituality and things (Think Like Me - 6)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-interview-and-spirituality-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 03:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-interview-and-spirituality-and-things/</guid>
      <description>Denis &amp;ldquo;interviews&amp;rdquo; me about Episode 3. We talk about a lot of stuff concerning Mormonism and spirituality in general, specifically how Muay Thai is like yoga and provides a lot of what religion didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be able to for us. Featuring a cameo by the lovely Mia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commonality Audits and canine interaction and things (Think Like Me - 5)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/commonality-audits-and-canine-interaction-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 03:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/commonality-audits-and-canine-interaction-and-things/</guid>
      <description>In this episode I introduce the new podcasting setup, go on a 30-minute rant about how people interact incorrectly with dogs (and give some practical tips on how to improve human-canine relations), give my two cents on a Gary Vaynerchuck quote, and discuss Commonality Audits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health and diet and things (Think Like Me - 4)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/health-and-diet-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 22:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/health-and-diet-and-things/</guid>
      <description>I talk about my physical transformation and my philosophy around health, nutrition, weight loss, and dieting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Divorce and my exodus from mormonism and things (Think Like Me - 3)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/divorce-and-my-exodus-from-mormonism-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 23:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/divorce-and-my-exodus-from-mormonism-and-things/</guid>
      <description>I tell the story of my divorce and why I left the Mormon church.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glory 31 Superfight Series Watching Party (Think Like Me - 2)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/glory-31-superfight-series-watching-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 23:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/glory-31-superfight-series-watching-party/</guid>
      <description>Me and Denis give our thoughts and breakdowns on the Glory 31 Superfight Series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honesty and things (Think Like Me - 1)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/honesty-and-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 23:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/honesty-and-things/</guid>
      <description>I ramble about some business stuff and then talk about being honest with yourself. Featuring a little stint on Facebook Live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying “No” to Business is More Valuable than Saying “Yes” - 4 Reasons Why</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/saying-no-to-business-is-more-valuable-than-saying-yes-4-reasons-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 19:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/saying-no-to-business-is-more-valuable-than-saying-yes-4-reasons-why/</guid>
      <description>Exclusivity is More Valuable than Inclusivity Nobody wants to be left out of the &amp;ldquo;cool kids&amp;rdquo; club. When your prospects understand that you don&amp;rsquo;t take everyone&amp;rsquo;s business, there is an immediate, subconscious desire to overcome whatever obstacles you&amp;rsquo;ve prepared for them. If you started your next sales pitch with something like, &amp;ldquo;Before I tell you what we do, I want you to know that we don&amp;rsquo;t work with everyone,&amp;rdquo; you immediately transform your business into one of those clubs that have bouncers with clipboards and very, very long lines of people eager to get in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Ego Can (and will) Hurt Your Customers</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/your-ego-can-and-will-hurt-your-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2013 19:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/your-ego-can-and-will-hurt-your-customers/</guid>
      <description>If you have any kind of customer service arm to your business (which should be all of you) it can be very easy to let your ego get in the way of what your customer really needs. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in the service business my whole career, and I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a trend where the service provider pushes very hard to assimilate the customer into their culture and system. Most of the time I would actually support this practice, in fact would say that the large majority of the time, it is very important to assimilate your customers into your way of thinking and doing things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with your Spouse: Tips to Make it Work</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/working-with-your-spouse-tips-to-make-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 18:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/working-with-your-spouse-tips-to-make-it-work/</guid>
      <description>I want to start by saying I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with a LOT of business owners whose right-hand man (or woman) was their husband (or wife), and I can count on 2 fingers the number of times it&amp;rsquo;s worked really well. Here are some tips to make it work better. A lot of these principles apply when working with other family members or even old friends.
Technicolor Type A The first thing you need to realize is that you are probably both pretty strong-willed and want to be in charge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Expectations: 4 Tips for Business Owners</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/setting-expectations-4-tips-for-business-owners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 18:38:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/setting-expectations-4-tips-for-business-owners/</guid>
      <description>Probably the most important principle in business is learning to set expectations. Between employees, non-employee resources, customers, prospects, and family members, a business owner has a lot of expectations to manage. It&amp;rsquo;s crucial that all of those expectations get set and maintained correctly for any business to function. Everyone needs to know what is expected of them and what to expect from you, and that can be overwhelming. That is why most small business owners tend to avoid setting expectations and just pray that they don&amp;rsquo;t end up with a customer or employee that eats up all of their time and resources because of poorly set expectations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I have passed the test?</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/should-i-have-passed-the-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 18:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/should-i-have-passed-the-test/</guid>
      <description>I took a biology class in college. I was/am terrible at biology, in case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, so this example will be perfect. The date of the first exam was coming up, so I began to study in preparation for it. Question: Should I have passed the test?
The obvious and probably first answer you&amp;rsquo;d think of is yes, I should have passed the test. We probably default to that because we all want to succeed and we want others to succeed, so it would make sense to think that I should have passed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Irony of Human Communication</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-irony-of-human-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 18:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-irony-of-human-communication/</guid>
      <description>You know, for supposedly being the only species capable of advanced communication, humans are really bad at communicating.
This isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be a rant or a rave about how some particular person angered me with their inability to communicate effectively. This is simply the expression of an idea that occurred to me today. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of the final piece to a puzzle where it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to really tell what the puzzle is until you have all of the pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Logic: a limerick</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/on-logic-a-limerick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 18:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/on-logic-a-limerick/</guid>
      <description>After my long quasi-rant that I went on in my previous post, I began to think about logic (naturally) and that led me to think of the professor who has taught and is still teaching me logic. He&amp;rsquo;s easily one of my favorite teachers ever, and yesterday he mentioned that when he is particularly frustrated or upset at something (or more often, someone) he writes limericks. He said that this really helps him to get out his frustration in a somewhat diffusing manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logic vs Intuition: the fatal confusion</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/logic-vs-intuition-the-fatal-confusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 18:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/logic-vs-intuition-the-fatal-confusion/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve become more and more aware recently of how often people claim to appeal to logic, when in fact they are appealing to intuition. The sad part is that most of the time, people don&amp;rsquo;t even realize what they&amp;rsquo;re doing. It turns out that about 99% of the time, people unwittingly disguise their own intuition as logic, and by so doing ascribe certain attributes and characteristics to logic that simply do not exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday Evening Thoughts (written on Tuesday morning)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/monday-evening-thoughts-written-on-tuesday-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 18:14:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/monday-evening-thoughts-written-on-tuesday-morning/</guid>
      <description>I think sometimes you just need to be ok with things not working out before you can really appreciate when they do.
People are always telling me that I should plan for the worst, that way when things do work out it will be that much more exciting. I always thought that was a little too pessimistic and depressing for me, so I never did it. I&amp;rsquo;ve always sort of expected the best things to happen, and when they don&amp;rsquo;t, I usually just push back until they at least kind of work out the way I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday Evening Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/sunday-evening-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 18:13:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/sunday-evening-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>This week has been one of reflection, as you can probably tell from my posts. Now, at the end of the week, I am thinking back on the week and I&amp;rsquo;m having even more thoughts (go figure). Here they are:
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided that, at the end of the day, life is about relationships. The only things that seem to really matter to people are their relationships with other people. We always hear stories about the rich people that don&amp;rsquo;t find solace in their money because they end up all alone with it, or the Hollywood stars who do crazy things because they don&amp;rsquo;t have real friends to turn to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A long overdue apology</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/a-long-overdue-apology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 18:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/a-long-overdue-apology/</guid>
      <description>I want to take a break from my grandstanding and say something that I should have said a long time ago. Really, I should have realized that this needed to be said a long time ago, but I&amp;rsquo;m stubborn and proud. I&amp;rsquo;m working on that.
My therapist says I&amp;rsquo;m an angry person. I think he&amp;rsquo;s right. Everything that I do and everything that happens to me is tinted by an underlying layer of anger that I&amp;rsquo;ve never fully understood (or tried to understand, for that matter).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Call to Reflection</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/a-call-to-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 18:09:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/a-call-to-reflection/</guid>
      <description>For the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a certain thought on my mind, and just recently it has developed into an opinion. Those of you who are unfortunate enough to know me are aware of the catastrophe that follows any instance of a thought becoming an opinion in my mind. Usually, I repeat my opinion ad nauseam to anyone that is bored enough or confined enough to sit through it. I think maybe this is my way of solidifying the opinion within myself, not unlike practice of a musical instrument solidifies the technique and notes in the musician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What would Beethoven and Bach say about contemporary music?</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/what-would-beethoven-and-bach-say-about-contemporary-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 18:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/what-would-beethoven-and-bach-say-about-contemporary-music/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking the other day about music, as I am very often doing, and I came to an interesting conclusion. Let’s see if I can recreate my thought process so this whole thing makes sense.
The first thought that I had was part of what I always thought was an interesting paradox of my tastes. I have observed that the average person these days has a particular type of music that they particularly like, and that they listen to almost exclusively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rule of Significant Figures as it Applies to Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-rule-of-significant-figures-as-it-applies-to-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 18:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-rule-of-significant-figures-as-it-applies-to-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>Many philosophers debate about what kinds of knowledge we can be sure about, or what counts as knowledge. In fact, they created an entire philosophical discipline dedicated to trying to figure that out. I’m not going to try and delve too far into that field, but I do have a theory that relates.
The big problem of Epistemology, at least as I see it, is that there is no real way to prove that we can know anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vindication, philosophically speaking</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/vindication-philosophically-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 18:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/vindication-philosophically-speaking/</guid>
      <description>Today has been a good day for philosophy and me. Over the past few weeks, our relationship has been pretty rocky, but there have been a few really good days that have made it worth it. Today has become a sort of day of vindication for the whole idea of me as a philosophy major. That of course doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that I love everything about philosophy or even agree with what&amp;rsquo;s being taught.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purism, Elitism, and Pure Stupidity</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/purism-elitism-and-pure-stupidity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 18:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/purism-elitism-and-pure-stupidity/</guid>
      <description>I want to try and stay away from too much diatribing; I want to have a lot of momentum when I really need it down the road ;)That being said, I wanted to bring up another question that I have been toying with in my head for a while. I think the title of this post not only gives away a good portion of the question, but also my personal stance, but I want to talk for a second about it and then see what you all think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honest vs. Abrasive (a diatribe on Facebook)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/honest-vs-abrasive-a-diatribe-on-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2010 18:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/honest-vs-abrasive-a-diatribe-on-facebook/</guid>
      <description>I’m not on very good terms with Facebook right now. I believe that it has single-handedly (or cyber-handedly, if you prefer) taken all conversational etiquette right out of our society. There is not one shred of the politeness that I have now come to really appreciate when I do actually encounter it.
Back story:
I posted the following as my status on Facebook about a month ago:
Watched &amp;ldquo;Everything is Illuminated&amp;rdquo; tonight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respect for Women (a diatribe)</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/respect-for-women-a-diatribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 18:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/respect-for-women-a-diatribe/</guid>
      <description>Recent events have gotten me thinking about a lot of the things that I think are seriously wrong with modern society, and I want to start listing them. There are a couple of people that will think that I wrote this aimed directly at them, but never fear, this has been on my mind for a lot longer than just today. This diatribe is directed at all people, everywhere.
I’ve come to the conclusion that our society has completely lost its sense of respect in general, but most blatantly (and most disgustingly), its respect for women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easier said than done</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/easier-said-than-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 18:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/easier-said-than-done/</guid>
      <description>I came to a shocking realization this morning, and it has a lot to do with a slight misunderstanding of that phrase, “easier said than done.” I think I’ve spent my whole life taking the easy way out. Let me explain:
Before this morning, I thought that the point of that phrase, “easier said than done,&amp;lsquo;” was focused on explaining one’s inability to perform or difficulty in performing an action by pointing out the relative difficulty of performing that task to giving it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My name is Bret Martineau and I approved this blog post.</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/my-name-is-bret-martineau-and-i-approved-this-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2010 17:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/my-name-is-bret-martineau-and-i-approved-this-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>I have a little catching up to do on my writing here, so these next few posts might come rapid-fire. I would apologize, but close to nobody reads this anyway so what difference does it make, right? One thing I’ve thought a lot about over the years is the concept of writing in pen versus writing in pencil. Let me explain. No, there is too much, let me sum up:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Dare You</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/i-dare-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 17:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/i-dare-you/</guid>
      <description>If you find yourself reading this post for whatever reason, I want you to know that I’m talking directly at you. This is a message for everyone collectively, but I am directing this more specifically at you. Don’t make the mistake of thinking that I’m referring to a specific person when I say that, because I am literally talking right at you. This is my challenge, in the form of a dare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discipline</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2010 17:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/discipline/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks or so ago I decided to start a new set of goals and plans so that my Summer would be productive and satisfying. I decided on exercise, eating, reading, cleaning, and all other types of goals you can think of. I thought about how we needed to develop the discipline to get everything done every day so that when the Fall semester rolls around again, I will have made those good habits and they will stick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homosexuality as a Physical Characteristic</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/homosexuality-as-a-physical-characteristic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 18:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/homosexuality-as-a-physical-characteristic/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
There is great confusion in the Latter-day Saint community surrounding and dealing with the issue of homosexuality and same-sex marriage. We have been instructed by our leaders that homosexuality is wrong and that we should support any proposition in defending marriage as being between a man and a woman. When this instruction was first given, I had serious doubts and troubles justifying this to myself. I could not justify that with what I knew concerning the equal protection clause of the 14th Amendment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “Fantasy World” of popular media</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-fantasy-world-of-popular-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2010 17:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/the-fantasy-world-of-popular-media/</guid>
      <description>Josh Gwynn brought up an interesting question one day while we were serving together in Ukraine, and I’ve thought a lot about it since. I was reminded of it today in Sunday school, so here it is:
Elder Gwynn was a much younger missionary, and so he had been in the States much more recently than I had, and therefore had a better idea of what “popular culture” was like. Because of this, and also because I was nearing the end of my mission, I would sometimes have him tell me the plot to movies that had come out since I had been in Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remember</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/remember/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 17:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/remember/</guid>
      <description>To my friends, family, and most importantly, myself:
Remember that people who are driving slowly in front of you are actually driving more legally than you are.
Remember that the faults you see in others are usually the things that you need to work on most.
Remember that waiting to let a long line of people or cars go before you go just lets them get to where they’re going a little bit faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>They call me amateur</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/they-call-me-amateur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2010 17:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/they-call-me-amateur/</guid>
      <description>They call me amateur,Who, from lofty perch of minded tradition Portray well the way of the ancients and Continue on as is the expectation. With citation of Byron and quotation of Shakespeare Flowing, eloquent, rehearsed and delivered, Bely they the foundation Upon which rest all thought to which they claim ownership.
I must confess, I do not share their understanding and knowledge. Nor do I claim to hold even a match-light to the passionate flame of Byron.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So what’s wrong with being sheltered again?</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/so-whats-wrong-with-being-sheltered-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 17:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/so-whats-wrong-with-being-sheltered-again/</guid>
      <description>I spent a good deal of time after I got back from Ukraine feeling very superior to everyone I met because I felt like I had “experience” of some kind. It seemed like everyone else I met was so stuck in their little bubble that they couldn’t see that there were other thoughts and ways of doing things. I think the biggest mistake I made was justifying my actions by telling people that they didn’t really know what “bad” was, because they hadn’t seen what I’d seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do, or do not; there is no try</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/do-or-do-not-there-is-no-try/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 17:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/do-or-do-not-there-is-no-try/</guid>
      <description>I’m sure there are very few of you who don’t know where this little line comes from. In fact, I think this may be among one of the most famous quotes of all time. I know it was very well known and very well used in our home, at least. Of course, that’s not the point that I’m getting at here.
I think that many people misunderstand this quote, and although I don’t consider a fictional alien character from a sci-fi movie to be the best source of wisdom for life, I think there is a lesson here for everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are no fresh starts or do-over’s, just fresh resolve and do-better’s</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/there-are-no-fresh-starts-or-do-overs-just-fresh-resolve-and-do-betters/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 17:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/there-are-no-fresh-starts-or-do-overs-just-fresh-resolve-and-do-betters/</guid>
      <description>With the New Year just past and everyone attempting to keep good on their new year’s resolutions, I think there is no better time for me to debut this little thought. I should preface this entire post with the fact that I have nothing against setting goals and I love the idea of setting resolutions for the New Year. I’m not advocating a change from that very worthwhile tradition, just a more accurate angle of approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be positive about everything and everyone</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/be-positive-about-everything-and-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2009 17:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/be-positive-about-everything-and-everyone/</guid>
      <description>When negative things are being said about someone, mention something you like about that person. Watch what happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Judge</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/dont-judge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 17:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/dont-judge/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re not qualified, and even if you were, someone else already got the job
Stephen Covey wrote a book about habits that effective people have. In that book, he talks a lot about paradigm and compares a person&amp;rsquo;s paradigm to a pair of colored glasses. He makes the point that the world looks a little bit different to a person with yellow lenses than it does to someone with red lenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Over Yourself</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/get-over-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 17:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/get-over-yourself/</guid>
      <description>*Everyone puts their pants on one leg at a time just like you do.
Every once in a while we meet someone who just thinks they are God&amp;rsquo;s gift to mankind. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s a co-worker who thinks they know everything there is to know about everything, or a fellow student who adores the sound of their own voice and thinks they have the answers to every question, or just a friend who is always looking down on you and making you feel 2 feet tall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Yourself</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/be-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2009 17:31:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/be-yourself/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s only one of you. We already have one of everyone else, and that&amp;rsquo;s enough.
So often these days people are so convinced that they aren&amp;rsquo;t good enough. We&amp;rsquo;re all set on &amp;ldquo;keeping up with the Jones&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; and making sure that we are &amp;ldquo;in&amp;rdquo; on the latest fads. We have to make it seem like we &amp;ldquo;fit in&amp;rdquo; so we try to act like those around us. There&amp;rsquo;s always one &amp;ldquo;leader&amp;rdquo; of every group, and in order to fit in with that group, we have to emulate the leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never talk negatively about someone you don’t know</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/never-talk-negatively-about-someone-you-dont-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 17:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/never-talk-negatively-about-someone-you-dont-know/</guid>
      <description>Why, stupid? You don&amp;rsquo;t know them!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been on both ends of this one enough to know a few things about why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do this. Negativity is never a really good thing, mostly because the whole idea behind negativity is the exact opposite of positive. While there are some who try to convince themselves and others that what is negative is actually good for them, the truth remains that negative always leaves you with less, while positive leaves you with more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You learn to do by doing; you learn to be by being</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/you-learn-to-do-by-doing-you-learn-to-be-by-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 17:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/you-learn-to-do-by-doing-you-learn-to-be-by-being/</guid>
      <description>Brad took a much more direct approach in his teaching, and frankly I loved his teaching method. It reminded me of Brigham Young, and I think that I have followed a lot in his footsteps. He was all about no-nonsense, just get it done tactics, and there was usually less psychology and reasoning and more just doing, which we&amp;rsquo;ll get to in the next lesson. Very often he would point out that the answers to most of life&amp;rsquo;s questions are fairly widely known, but people don&amp;rsquo;t recognize them because they are so common place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to love silence</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/learn-to-love-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 17:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/learn-to-love-silence/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a while, when you&amp;rsquo;re driving late at night, turn off the music and just listen to the city. You&amp;rsquo;ll be surprised at what happens.
I actually did this one time. It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly short story, but it illustrates the point I think.
One night I was driving home late and as usual, had my music on way loud and was just having a great time, and then I remembered what Dad always said about turning the music off, so at one intersection, I decided to try it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treat people like they already are what you want them to become</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/treat-people-like-they-already-are-what-you-want-them-to-become/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 17:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/treat-people-like-they-already-are-what-you-want-them-to-become/</guid>
      <description>Dad is my hero for so many reasons, but I think the biggest reason is because in so many ways I want to be able to be half the father he was to me to my children. He always has had such a way with people, and not only have I never heard anyone say a single bad thing about him, I have never once heard him say anything negative about anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There are 2 kinds of pain: the Pain of Discipline and the Pain of Regret</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/there-are-2-kinds-of-pain-the-pain-of-discipline-and-the-pain-of-regret/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 17:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/there-are-2-kinds-of-pain-the-pain-of-discipline-and-the-pain-of-regret/</guid>
      <description>I think this was mom&amp;rsquo;s favorite quote, and she adopted it sometime during my sophomore or junior year of high school. This one has had more application in my life than any other phrase or idea I think. In fact, I have spread this around, and now it&amp;rsquo;s pretty well known in some areas.
It basically explains itself, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to do it justice:
For every situation, there are usually a few different options as far as what you can do in that situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean the corners, and the middle will take care of itself</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/clean-the-corners-and-the-middle-will-take-care-of-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 17:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/clean-the-corners-and-the-middle-will-take-care-of-itself/</guid>
      <description>One Saturday I was in the middle of my weekly &amp;ldquo;responsibilities&amp;rdquo; at home and, as usual, I was dragging my feet to do a complete job. I had a particular problem doing chores all the way, and I think it annoyed mom quite a bit. I would never quite do the job completely. I would always clean up the big obvious parts of the room that I was supposed to clean, but often the little details would be completely forgotten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>White Men: A Social Commentary</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/white-men-a-social-commentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 17:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/white-men-a-social-commentary/</guid>
      <description>An episode of 30 Rock (amazingly hilarious show) brought up a very interesting point. Two characters, one a black man (Tracy Jordan played by Tracy Morgan), and one a white woman (Jenna Maroney played by Jane Krakowski), argue over who has it &amp;ldquo;harder&amp;rdquo; in life because of social oppression, black people or women. The reach a point where to prove their respective points, they &amp;ldquo;switch places&amp;rdquo;. Tracy Jordan dons makeup and a blond wig to become a white woman, while Jenna dresses up like a black man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you think I’m sexist…..</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/if-you-think-im-sexist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 17:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/if-you-think-im-sexist/</guid>
      <description>So I was in my writing class today (it&amp;rsquo;s actually a philosophy class but that has nothing to do with anything) and my professor pointed something out that I simply will not accept. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with my professor; he&amp;rsquo;s a great man. He just happens to be the guy who has to say these ridiculous things.
So we are talking about grammar and spelling and things and we were each given a paper with statements that supposedly had grammatical errors that we were to correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PDA….is ok!</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/pda-is-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 17:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/pda-is-ok/</guid>
      <description>I want to preface this by saying that I did not write this with any particular person in mind. Some of you may think that I wrote this directly to you, and that’s not really the case. There have been so many instances in my life that have led up to me writing this, so to pin it on one person or instance would be both unfair and illogical. This is merely a statement of opinion, my opinion, and all comments and rebuttals and support is welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Men and Women are Perfect for Each Other</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/why-men-and-women-are-perfect-for-each-other/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 16:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/why-men-and-women-are-perfect-for-each-other/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a matter of intense debate and discussion, this battle between the sexes. For centuries, men and women of all ages have been trying to prove that their sex, referring to gender, is superior to the other. My point here is to show how no matter how you construe it, neither of the sexes is any better than the other, and how amazingly well men and women complement each other, and in so doing, answer the posed question, why are men and women perfect for each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To the wandering child</title>
      <link>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/to-the-wandering-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 17:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bretwardjames.com/blog/to-the-wandering-child/</guid>
      <description>O thou wanderer Thine heart in doubt, Whither thou goest Knowest thou not? This path that thou treadest, With darkness beset, Leadeth not to that rest, Which thou wishest to get.
O thou wanderer, Thou goest to and fro Searching here and searching there, But for what, thou dost not know. O beloved daughter, Seest thou the end? Treacherous is the resolution Of that trail which you descend.
O thou wanderer, Wilt thou suffer long?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>